

SKILL SET

Azure Cloud:

- Azure Kubernetes Service
- Azure PaaS service
- AKS Architect and Design
- Load Balancing
- Virtual Private Network (VPN)
- Azure Cloud Services
- Azure Virtual Machines
- Azure Active Directory
- Azure Resource Manager
- Technical support and assistance

DevOps Tools:

 Docker and Kubernetes, Azure DevOps, GitHub, SonarQube, Jira, Bitbucket

Operating System:

UNIX and Linux and Windows

Middleware:

- IBM WebSphere Application Server (WAS) 8.5.5, WebLogic server, MQ 5.3 &
 6.0
- ➤ Monitoring Tools: Dynatrace Client 6.5,

Ticketing tools:

Service-Now and Remedy

Programming Languages:

Knowledge in Java /J2EE

CERTIFICATIONS

August 2018 - AWS Solution Architect-

Associate



November 2022-Azure Administration-AZ104



December 2022-Azure Solution Architect-305



December 2007 - ITIL® Foundation in IT

Service Management

June 2008 Sun Certified Java Programmer

(SCJP

SyamSundar B

Azure Solution Architect

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Over all 16 years of experience. 6+ years of experience as Azure Solution architect and Azure Cloud Engineer along with 10 years of experience in Server Administration, Software Configuration Management, experienced with developing automated cloud platform scripts for integrating web applications. Looking for a position in an organization to provide customized solutions and improve business operations.

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES

Solution Architect and Cloud Migration Lead

- Experience in designing and implementation of Azure Kubernetes architecture collaboration with Kong API and front load
- Designed and implemented the Azure App-Service architecture and solution
- Leading a technical team of cloud migration across PaaS and laaS platforms.
- Migration planning exercises and effort estimation for projects/ proposals
- Documentation of solutions (e.g., architecture, HLD / LLD, configuration and setup).
- Strong experience in Azure Site Recovery and Azure Migrate.
- Experience in large Datacenter migrations to Azure or other public cloud platforms.
- Experience in Microsoft Azure Operational and Monitoring tools.
- Understand existing (On-Prem) Application Architecture and providing the solutions for cloud enabling application.
- Microsoft Azure and its relevant build, deployment, networking, and security technologies in hybrid cloud environments.
- Knowledge Windows Virtual Machines and Linux machines.
- Knowledge of deployment orchestration and configuration management tools (Jenkins, Terraform, Kubernetes).
- Experienced in the design and delivery of enterprise level Highly Available solutions.
- Assisting in providing post migration support for customers.
- Customer collaboration on migration and discovery workshops and documentation.
- Mentoring junior members of the Azure migration team.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

March 2019 – Present Azure Solution Architect & Azure Cloud Engineer TCS- Bangalore, India

- Leading the team as a solution architect in a large Banking and Health care Domains
- Design and implemented the Azure Kubernetes architecture with Hub and Spoke model in collaboration with Kong API.
- Design and implemented the Azure PaaS architecture and solution
- Customer collaboration on migration and discovery workshops and documentation.
- Architecting Microsoft Azure Solutions across multiple technologies such as Microsoft, Open Source.
- Lead a Solutions Architecture team consisting of 6 members to develop 4 applications and services on the Azure platform and improve customer success
- Adhere strictly to all company and state-wide servers, network security, and application compliance requirements
- Collaborate with regional and global IT support teams to resolve technical difficulties and follow up on IT support requests, resulting in a 35% increase in resolved cases
- Provided solution for lift and shift, refactoring the applications.

January 2018 – March 2019 Azure Cloud Migration Lead & Azure DevOps Lead TCS- Sweden, Denmark, and Bangalore

- Leading a technical team of cloud migration across PaaS and IaaS platforms.
- Migration planning exercises and effort estimation for projects/ proposals
- Documentation of solutions (e.g., architecture, configuration, and setup).
- Developed and implemented solutions for scaling, performance improvement, monitoring, and systems configuration management
- Created secure zones for organization in the Azure public cloud using security groups, network ACLs, route tables, and internet getaways
- Experienced in deploying Web Apps and Creating Web-Jobs Sync on premises Active Directory users to office 365 with AD Connect and ADFS to make easy to user moving.
- Experience in large Data-Centre migrations to Azure or other public cloud platforms.
- Experience in Microsoft Azure Operational and Monitoring tools.
- Provided solution for cloud enabling application as lift and shift, refactoring the applications.

May 2016 – January 2018 Cloud Migration Assessment Lead & WebSphere application server admin TCS- Munich, Germany

- Cloud migration assessment lead and worked as WebSphere application server admin for a Large Insurance firm
- Found and Applied solutions while migrating the legacy applications (like legacy EJB applications and WAS 6.x versions and so on)
- Provided the assessment on migrating the WAS based applications to cloud Docker and AWS
- Deployment with source repository GitHub different environments.
- Worked in CI/CD Pipeline in deployment of applications and monitoring
- Responsible for collaborating with developers to build code, manage issues, and successfully deploy our software.
- To identify root cause for high repose from environment / server by using Performance MUC tool
- There is 40 % of improvement is identified with effect of multithreaded jobs in from application side
- There is 20% EOD/EOM batch process improvement with performance optimization from database and multiple performance tests which are performed during my project period.
- Extensively worked in Dynatrace monitoring and fixing the application performance issues

May 2012 – April 2016 WebSphere application server admin & Performance Engineer TCS – Bangalore, India

- Worked as performance Engineer and WebSphere application server admin lead for a Large Insurance firm
- Supporting for 200 + applications on 500+ servers which includes Testing and Production environment
- Integration, production support for E-Portal, Classic Cell, and Enterprise service Bus projects.
- Troubleshooting and finding the root cause analysis using the Dynatrace for the issues on all the environments.
- Application server tuning. More frequent monitoring the CPU load GC Suspension times and connection pool size for various environments
- Heap and Thread dump analysis and provide the analysis results to corresponding application owners.
- Opening the PMRs and working with IBM in resolving the issues.
- Involving in Incident calls with incident management team with respect to B2, B3tickets.
- Monitoring Dynatrace tool to identify the issues in depth.
- Certificate updates/renewals and deployments
- Coordination with another team's portal core, DevOps when required
- Incident and change management process for application support activities
- Support the ESB application Load tests and shared the results with corresponding teams
- Coordination with IBM and ESB application owners with respect to ESB related issues on regular basis
- ESB support activities for all the stages (deployment, certificate, CPU high load, etc issues)

January 2010 – April 2012 WebSphere/WebLogic application server/Tomcat server Admin TCS – Bangalore, India

- Developed firewalls and multi-tiered architectures.
- Participated in architecting, test and initiate upgrades and patches.
- Participated in supporting new application development, manage and execute assigned tasks.
- Performed and initiated QA audits.
- Responsible in developing WebSphere cells, clusters, and nodes. Creating and testing applications.
- Developing firewalls and multi-tiered architectures.
- Testing and implementing upgrades and patches.
- Planning and performing QA audits.
- Configuring and testing production environments. And provided the extended production support.

June 2006 – December 2011 Java/J2EE developer TCS – Bangalore, India

- Application development and enhancing in Java/J2EE
- Planning, designing, enhancement, integration, production support of customer applications which are hosted on WebSphere and WebLogic servers.
- Understand business requirement and convert into technical specifications
- Monitor performance and implement innovative solutions to improve overall system
- Perform regular checks and follow best practices to develop, deploy, and maintain the application
- Constantly monitor and identify production and non-production issues and resolve them
- Configure and test production environments.
- Execute functions on WebSphere application server v.6.

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATION
 September 2004 Master of Computer Applications (MCA), Visvesvaraya Technological University, Bangalore (Karnataka) India June 2001 Bachelor of Science in Computer Science (BSC), Sri Krishnadevaraya University, Anantapur, Andhra Pradesh), India. June 2010 Master of Business Administration (MBA), Sikkim Manipal University-Distance Education, India